Amri Rasyidi

amri.geodesy@gmail.com



Summary

Bachelor of Science in Geodesy and Geomatics Engineering with over 6 years of experience in the data industry. Strong passion for spatial data science and computer vision. Proven leadership skills and a commitment to continuous learning and knowledge sharing through active volunteering as a data science mentor.

Professional Experience

ESRI Indonesia (GIS Software & Services)

Jakarta, Indonesia

Data Scientist

January 2023 - present

Esri Indonesia provides GIS solutions and services to various industries in Indonesia, including local and national government, natural resources, utilities, transportation, telecommunications, and commercial.

- Custom Web-based Computer Vision Application: Led a team of 4 engineers to successfully develop and deploy a custom web-based computer vision application within 7 weeks, utilizing Python API for ArcGIS to build and deploy deep learning models. The initial model achieved 82% mean Average Precision (mAP).
- Automated Computer Vision System: Spearheaded the end-to-end development of a system, including building the back-end service to receive submissions from a mobile app, developing a deep learning model for object detection, and creating a dashboard for real-time reporting and insights.
- Palm Tree Counting: Led a palm tree counting project, overseeing data labeling of over 7000 data points on drone imageries, consulting with the reporting, and utilizing ArcGIS Pro for data preparation. Trained a deep learning model and managed performance analysis, resulting in an exceptional 95% mean Average Precision (mAP).
- GIS-Based Market Development: collaborated with the solution team to develop a dashboard able to showcase current market presence and potential leads. Created a custom data processing pipeline capable of handling 193 million records, reducing manual process time by 72%. Applied a statistical method to classify ~300 top priority leads out of 4000 prospects

Zenius Education (Ed-Tech)

Jakarta, Indonesia

Business Intelligence Analyst

December 2021 - July 2022

Zenius is a well-known ed-tech company pioneer focused on increasing thinking capacity and building foundational thinking for junior and senior high school student to help them excel in their school.

- Workflow management: structured a system to increase workflow transparency and accountability. Increased the ability to manage and monitor ad hoc and internal tasks/projects from 0 to 16+ tasks/projects weekly.
- Dashboard: created 3 dashboards with Google Data Studio for growth, finance, and content teams with over 50 metrics ranging from operational to C-level granularity.

Gojek (Q-commerce and Financial Services)

Jakarta, Indonesia

$Junior\ Risk\ Data\ Analyst \Rightarrow Risk\ Data\ Analyst$

April 2019 - December 2021

GoTo's ecosystem comprises of on-demand transport, e-commerce, food, and grocery delivery, logistics and fulfillment, and financial services through the Gojek, Tokopedia and GoTo Financial platforms.

- Fraud analysis: analyzed up to 1000 GPS movements daily to determine fraudulent patterns for constructing fraud rules of fourwheels and two-wheel platforms.
- Rule deployment: prevented new modus operandi from exploiting a GPS related-loophole in the production apps. Fraudsters abused this loophole for financial gain and reputation hijack. Reduced the number of case significantly from 400 to 10 cases daily, with a false positive rate under 1\% within a month.
- Rule enhancement: analyzed the hypothesis made fraud my team then enhanced the rule by applying a more sophisticated method of fraud identification (relational graph logic) to detect the convoluted device connection/relation. Increased the detection rate by 50%.

Project

Land Cover Segmentation (?)

(Rasterio, RioXarray, Sklearn)

- Used random forest classification to classify land cover from Sentinel-2 imagery
- The model achieved accuracy of 97%

Palm Tree Detection (7)

(PyTorch)

- Identify palm trees in aerial imagery captured by drones
- Implemented pre-processing techniques for drone imagery and developed a custom training data processing pipeline
- Fine-tuned the Mask R-CNN model to achieve robust performance.

Skills and Tech Stack

- Machine Learning, Deep Learning, MLOps: PyTorch, YOLO, XGBoost, MLFlow, Optuna,
- Data Science: VSCode, GeoPandas, Rasterio, duckdb, polars, BigQuery SQL, ArcGIS Pro
- Others: Git, GitHub
- Relevant coursework: computer vision (image classification, object detection), spatial analysis, time series forecasting, classification
- Languages: Bahasa Indonesia (Native), English (CEFR Level C1/IELTS 7.5).

Achievement

- ESRI ArcGIS Pro Associate: proof of experience in applying ArcGIS concepts and processes to workflows. Demonstrated proficiency using ArcGIS to manage, analyze, and manipulate geospatial data. [Certificate]
- Neo4j Certified Professional: official professional certification from Neo4j. [Certificate]
- Panelist ASEAN Geospatial Challenge: a national level competition on geospatial solution and innovation. Involved as a panel in evaluating top 10 submissions. [Certificate]

Education

MIT IDSS: Data Science and Machine Learning

Remote

An online professional course taught by the MIT faculty

August - November 2022

Topic covered: statistics, unsupervised and supervised learning, hypothesis testing, deep learning, recommendation system, network and graphical model, and predictive analysis.

Institut Teknologi Bandung

Bandung, Indonesia

B.Sc in Geodesy and Geometrics Engineering, GPA 3.21/4.00.

July 2014 - October 2018

Topic covered includes: calculus, statistics, GIS, satellite geodesy, remote sensing, spatial database, cartography.

Leadership/Voluntary Experience

Dealls

Remote

Mentor

July 2024 - Present

Dealls is Indonesia's leading job portal, offering high-quality job listings from over 3,500 top companies. It also provides free career development programs, including mentoring and CV review services, to help job seekers secure their dream careers more easily.

• Super Mentor: guiding professionals in navigating their career in the data industry. Provides a free-of-service career consultation.

RevoU x MSIB

Remote

Mentor

February - April 2024

RevoU is Indonesia's Largest Professional Skilling Platform. MSIB is a comprehensive career preparation program initiated by ministry of education and culture.

• Mentorship: guiding students interested in pursuing careers as data analysts and data scientists. Conducted live sessions to provide technical skills, while also creating comprehensive learning materials to support their journey into the tech field.

Yayasan Anak Bangsa Bisa (YABB)

Jakarta, Indonesia

Mentor/Instructor - Generasi Gigih

July - $December\ 2021$

Yayasan Anak Bangsa Bisa (YABB) is a non-profit organization founded by Gojek, a catalyst that enables resilient change makers to solve pressing challenges and build sustainable communities. Generasi Gigih programme focuses on generating tech-talent by conducting an intensive boot camp to prepare fresh graduates for the tech industry.

- Designed, created, and lectured: data analysis lecture materials (Python and SQL for data analysis).
- Mentorship: guide and mentor the participants during their internship. Ensured the participants gained the most during their internship while maintaining the focus on the projects they were working on.

Ikatan Mahasiswa Geodesi ITB (IMG-ITB)

Bandung, Indonesia

Chairman of IMG-ITB (Executive Student Council)

August 2017 - March 2018

Ikatan Mahasiswa Geodesi ITB (IMG-ITB) is a profession-based student association.

- Visioning: designed a blueprint as the north star metrics of the association. Mainly focus on character and mindset development in a professional manner and making a concrete social impact.
- Executive function: managed a council consisting of 5 ministries and 15 departments to maintain and develop the student association.

Miscellaneous

- Topic: education, environment, game industry, movie, leisure.
- Book: history, sociology, biography, religion, psychology.
- Activity: SCUBA diving, hiking, gym, PC game, writing.